José Gregorio Lezama González

Technical Lead & Web Developer



https://joseglego.io/

Santiago de Chile, Chile Remote & Willing to Relocate

Last Update: Sep 20, 2017

SUMMARY

I am a passionate developer and a coffee lover.

As a developer, I have experience in **back-end** and **front-end**. I am interested in learning new technologies. I like to follow the best practices of each new language or framework. I enjoy front-end development, working with good eye for details and working for a good look and feel & UX. Also, I really like to work back-end. So, I can work full-stack.

My last works were in: Front-End & UX, Back-End, Web Mobile, a little of Automation & Admin.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer & Architect (Freelancer)

Datos MEG | Sep 2015 - Present. Part-Time

Working in a Web & Web Mobile app with a RESTful API server. I'm working as a developer / admin of multiple servers / architect / UX developer / software designer. I'm like a Ninja Developer.

Technical Lead & Developer

Cleteci | Feb 2017 - Aug 2017

Mentoring up to 9 developers, reviewing code and supporting them. Supporting QA team fixing issues related to next release and production. Investigation of new tools & technologies to improve the quality of the environment, code and product. Defining higher standards for code, product & documentation. Supporting thirds companies integrations. Continuous working on refactoring.

Scrum Master & Developer

Cleteci | Jan 2016 - Jan 2017

Mentoring up to 5 developers, reviewing code and supporting them. Supporting QA team fixing issues related to next release and production. Continuous working on refactoring and including new tools and technologies.

Web Developer

Cleteci | Sep 2014 - Dec 2015

Developing new features on RESTful APIS with clients applications and classic web applications.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Engineering

Simón Bolívar University | Sep 2007 - Nov 2015

Internship: Web System for <u>AtrioSeguros</u> Agents (Insurance Company) - with Honors

Specialization: 1. Databases, **2.** Computer Graphics & **3.** Software Development Workshop: A Medical Emergencies Software, <u>iTriage</u> - <u>Current Version</u>.

Electives: 1. Mobile Development, **2.** Software Methodologies, **3. & 4.** A.I. on Robotics and on Video Games, **5.** Computer Graphics on Video Games & **6.** A.R.

PROJECTS

Travel Contact

A travel management & Agency travel management *startup*. Rails, AngularJS and Ionic

Latch

A smart access system **startup.** AngularJS

Phoebe

A photo studio sales app. Django & jQuery

Atrio Seguros

An Insurance Agents app. AngularJS, Oracle & Java

Datos MEG

A RESTful API with web and web mobile clients. Django + DRF, Ionic and AngularJS

TECHNOLOGIES & TOOLS | Preferences on Bold

Base

OS X - Linux, Windows, Python, Javascript, Ruby, Java, C/C++, Bash, Haskell, Prolog.

Web

AngularJS, Gulp, Bower, HTML, CSS, JS, Lodash, jQuery, Bootstrap, Grunt, Django, Ruby on Rails, Node, Express.

Tools

lonic/Phonegap, **Emacs**, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, **git**, **Photoshop**, Illustrator, Agile/**Scrum**, **Heroku**, **AWS**, Linode, DigitalOcean.

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Daily English Lessons, 3 hours. | Aug 2016 - Present

Urban Data Fest (<u>Venezuela</u>): 3rd Place, <u>Monitorea.la</u>: front-end developer | Mar 2015

CodeSchool: Courses of JavaScript (10), Ruby (2), HTML/CSS (4) & others (3) | 2014 - Present

LANGUAGES

Spanish - Native speaker **English** - Upper Intermediate